<?xml version="1.0"?>
<!DOCTYPE document [
  <!ENTITY project SYSTEM "project.xml">
]>
<document url="index.html"> &project; <properties>
    <author email="mladen.turk@jboss.com">Mladen Turk</author>
    <title>Overview</title>
  </properties>
  <body>

    <section name="Introduction">
      <p>JBoss Web Server is an enterprise ready web server designed for medium and large applications, based on the<a
          href="http://tomcat.apache.org">Apache Tomcat</a>. It is meant to be used as a replacement for the standard
        Web servers on all major platforms. JBoss Web Server provides organizations with a single deployment platform
        for Java Server Pages (JSP) and Java Servlet technologies, Microsoft .NET, PHP, and CGI. It uses a genuine high
        performance hybrid technology that incorporates the best of the most recent OS technologies for processing high
        volume data, while keeping all the reference Java specifications. It supports both in and out of the process
        execution of CGI and PHP scripts, as well as .NET applications. The hybrid technology model offers the best from
        threading and event processing models, and that makes the JBoss Web Server one of the fastest and most scalable
        web servers in the market.</p>
      <br/>
    </section>
    <section name="Performance">
      <p>JBoss Web Server can be used as a high performance generic web server instead of common native
      web servers like Apache Httpd or IIS.
      </p>
      <p>Compared with Apache Tomcat it offers a significant performance improvements, especially
      with serving secure (SSL) content. Since JBoss Web Server uses industry standard OpenSSL  it
      provides 3-4 times (!) better performance when compared with any Java based web server.
      </p>
      <figure src="/images/benchmarks/10kssl.png" name="Figure 1" text="SSL benckmark (x86_64 GNU/Linux)"/>
      <br/>
    </section>
    <section name="Technology">
      <p>JBoss Web Server uses <a href="http://apr.apache.org">Apache APR</a> that gives platform
      independance and modern OS technologies like sendfile support that lowers the CPU usage
      and thus offers the higer permomance/cost ratio.
      </p>
      <p>
        <image src="/images/jboss_ics.gif"/>
        <image src="/images/tomcat_pb.gif"/>
        <image src="/images/openssl_ics.gif"/>
        <image src="/images/jbweb_pb.gif"/>
      </p>
      <br/>
    </section>
  </body>
</document>
