<?xml version="1.0"?>
<!DOCTYPE document [
  <!ENTITY project SYSTEM "project.xml">
]>
<document url="index.html"> &project; <properties>
    <author email="mladen.turk@jboss.com">Mladen Turk</author>
    <title>JBossWeb Features</title>
  </properties>
  <body>

    <section name="The Best of Tomcat and Apache">

      <p>Many users of Tomcat in JBoss choose to place a native web server like Apache in front of Tomcat to handle
        client requests on behalf of the Tomcat. Using a native server can yield better overall performance in many
        cases. Native networking and SSL libraries can outperform the current Java implementations, and static content
        can often be delivered to the clients in a much more efficient manner. Native web servers can provide more
        advanced management options and also offer a variety of non-Java application options.</p>
      <p>JBoss Web Server integrates the flexibility and power of the Apache web server into Tomcat. This integration
        brings the most recent OS technologies for processing high volume data available to web applications in JBoss,
        making the JBoss Web Server one of the fastest and most scalable web servers in the market. </p>

      <subsection name="Full Java EE Support">The power of JBoss Web comes with full Java EE support. JBoss Web supports
        the JSP 2.0 and Servlet 2.4 specifications, providing a complete web development environment. JBoss Web runs in
        the same VM as the JBoss application server, providing a complete environment for everything from simple web
        applications to complex high-end enterprise applications. </subsection>
      <subsection name="Highly Scalable">JBoss Web scales to the levels required by the most demanding of applications.
        The hybrid connection model can handle client loads of 10,000+ concurrent connections. </subsection>
      <subsection name="Fast Static Content">JBoss Web takes advantage of fast OS-specific features to achieve zero-copy
        transfer of static content. This decreases CPU load and improves application responsiveness. </subsection>
      <subsection name="Clustering Support">JBoss Web can serve an amazing number of requests on a single machine, but
        when you need to scale beyond that, JBoss Web is there. JBoss web offers full clustering support for web
        applications. JBoss Web HTTP session replication is based on the powerful JBossCache technology, allowing your
        application state to be efficiently shared between all the nodes in your application cluster. </subsection>
      <subsection name="OpenSSL Support">The security of your web application matters. SSL is the cornerstone of web
        security, but Java SSL engines are slow and can put a big burden on your CPU. JBossWeb integrates the native
        OpenSSL libraries, the fastest and most secure open source SSL implementation. The highly-optimized OpenSSL
        libraries also allow for hardware acceleration which yield a ten fold performance increase. </subsection>
      <subsection name="URL Rewriting">JBoss Web provides a powerful URL rewriting module, similar to Apache
        mod_rewrite. URLs can be rewritten to support legacy URLs, handle errors or rapidly respond to web application
        issues that come up in the hectic day-to-day management of web applications. </subsection>

      <subsection name="Integration">JBoss Web Server provides organizations with a single deployment platform for the
        most common types of web applications. Not only does JBoss Web support the latest Java web technologies, but
        JBoss web can also support applications running on Microsoft .NET, PHP, and CGI. There is no longer any need to
        manage multiple servers for multiple web platforms. Legacy applications can maintained on JBoss Web, right along
        side your other applications. New development can take advantage of powerful features of any of these web
        platforms. JBoss Web gives you the power to choose the right platform for each task, and total flexibility to
        make changes along the way. </subsection>
    </section>

  </body>
</document>
