<?xml version="1.0"?>
<!DOCTYPE document [
  <!ENTITY project SYSTEM "project.xml">
]>
<document url="http.html">

  &project;

  <properties>
    <author email="craigmcc@apache.org">Craig R. McClanahan</author>
    <author email="yoavs@apache.org">Yoav Shapira</author>
    <author email="jfclere@apache.org">Jean-Frederic Clere</author>
    <title>The HTTP Connector</title>
  </properties>

<body>


<section name="Introduction">

  <p>The <strong>HTTP Connector</strong> element represents a
  <strong>Connector</strong> component that supports the HTTP/1.1 protocol.
  It enables Catalina to function as a stand-alone web server, in addition
  to its ability to execute servlets and JSP pages.  A particular instance
  of this component listens for connections on a specific TCP port number
  on the server.  One or more such <strong>Connectors</strong> can be
  configured as part of the <a href="subsystem.html">Web subSystem</a>
  to perform request processing and create the response.</p>

  <p>If you wish to configure the <strong>Connector</strong> that is used
  for connections to web servers using the AJP protocol (such as the
  <code>mod_jk 1.2.x</code> connector for Apache 1.3), see
  <a href="ajp.html">here</a> instead.</p>

  <p>Each incoming request requires
  a thread for the duration of that request.  If more simultaneous requests
  are received than can be handled by the currently available request
  processing threads, additional threads will be created up to the
  configured maximum (the value of the <code>max-connections</code> attribute).
  Additional connections will be rejected.</p>

</section>


<section name="Attributes">

  <subsection name="Common Attributes">

  <p>All implementations of <strong>Connector</strong>
  support the following attributes:</p>

  <attributes>
 
    <attribute name="name" required="true">
      <p>Name of the connector</p>
    </attribute>

    <attribute name="enable-lookups" required="false">
      <p>Set to <code>true</code> if you want calls to
      <code>request.getRemoteHost()</code> to perform DNS lookups in
      order to return the actual host name of the remote client.  Set
      to <code>false</code> to skip the DNS lookup and return the IP
      address in String form instead (thereby improving performance).
      By default, DNS lookups are enabled.</p>
    </attribute>

    <attribute name="max-post-size" required="false">
      <p>The maximum size in bytes of the POST which will be handled by
      the container FORM URL parameter parsing. The limit can be disabled by
      setting this attribute to a value less than or equal to 0.
      If not specified, this attribute is set to 2097152 (2 megabytes).</p>
    </attribute>

    <attribute name="max-save-post-size" required="false">
      <p>The maximum size in bytes of the POST which will be saved/buffered by
      the container during FORM or CLIENT-CERT authentication. For both types
      of authentication, the POST will be saved/buffered before the user is
      authenticated. For CLIENT-CERT authentication, the POST is buffered for
      the duration of the SSL handshake and the buffer emptied when the request
      is processed. For FORM authentication the POST is saved whilst the user
      is re-directed to the login form and is retained until the user
      successfully authenticates or the session associated with the
      authentication request expires. The limit can be disabled by setting this
      attribute to -1. Setting the attribute to zero will disable the saving of
      POST data during authentication and the buffering during SSL handshake. 
      If not specified, this attribute is set to 4096 (4 kilobytes).</p>
    </attribute>

    <attribute name="protocol" required="false">
      <p>
        Sets the protocol to handle incoming traffic.
        The default value is <code>HTTP/1.1</code> and configures the 
        <code>org.apache.coyote.http11.Http11Protocol</code>. This is the blocking Java connector.<br/>
        If the <code>PATH(Windows)</code> or <code>LD_LIBRARY_PATH(on most unix system)</code>  
        environment variables contain the Tomcat native library, the APR connector
        will automatically be configured. Please be advised that the APR connector has different
        settings for HTTPS than the default Java connector.<br/>
        Other values for this attribute are, but not limited to:<br/>
        <code>org.apache.coyote.http11.Http11Protocol</code> - same as HTTP/1.1<br/>
        <code>org.apache.coyote.http11.Http11NioProtocol</code> - non blocking Java connector, not supported in JBossWeb<br/>
        <code>org.apache.coyote.http11.Http11AprProtocol</code> - the APR connector.<br/>
        Take a look at our <a href="#Connector Comparison">Connector Comparison</a> chart.
        The configuration for both Java connectors are identical, both for http and https. <br/>
        For more information on the APR connector and APR specific SSL settings please 
        visit the <a href="../apr.html">APR documentation</a>
        
      </p>
    </attribute>

    <attribute name="proxy-name" required="false">
      <p>If this <strong>Connector</strong> is being used in a proxy
      configuration, configure this attribute to specify the server name
      to be returned for calls to <code>request.getServerName()</code>.
      See <a href="#Proxy Support">Proxy Support</a> for more
      information.</p>
    </attribute>

    <attribute name="proxy-port" required="false">
      <p>If this <strong>Connector</strong> is being used in a proxy
      configuration, configure this attribute to specify the server port
      to be returned for calls to <code>request.getServerPort()</code>.
      See <a href="#Proxy Support">Proxy Support</a> for more
      information.</p>
    </attribute>

    <attribute name="redirect-port" required="false">
      <p>If this <strong>Connector</strong> is supporting non-SSL
      requests, and a request is received for which a matching
      <code>&lt;security-constraint&gt;</code> requires SSL transport,
      Catalina will automatically redirect the request to the port
      number specified here.</p>
    </attribute>

    <attribute name="ssl" required="false">
      <p>
      Use this element to enable SSL traffic on a connector.
      To turn on SSL handshake/encryption/decryption on a connector.
      When present you will want to set the 
      <code>scheme</code> and the <code>secure</code> attributes as well
      to pass the correct <code>request.getScheme()</code> and 
      <code>request.isSecure()</code> values to the servlets
      See <a href="#SSL Support">SSL Support</a> for more information.
      </p>
    </attribute>

    <attribute name="scheme" required="false">
      <p>Set this attribute to the name of the protocol you wish to have
      returned by calls to <code>request.getScheme()</code>.  For
      example, you would set this attribute to "<code>https</code>"
      for an SSL Connector.  The default value is "<code>http</code>".
      </p>
    </attribute>

    <attribute name="secure" required="false">
      <p>Set this attribute to <code>true</code> if you wish to have
      calls to <code>request.isSecure()</code> to return <code>true</code>
      for requests received by this Connector. You would want this on an
      SSL Connector or a non SSL connector that is receiving data from a 
      SSL accelerator, like a crypto card, a SSL appliance or even a webserver.
      The default value is <code>false</code>.</p>
    </attribute>

    <attribute name="enabled" required="false">
      <p>Set this attribute to <code>false</code> if you don't wan the
      Connector to be used.
      The default value is <code>true</code>.</p>
    </attribute>

    <attribute name="executor" required="false">
      <p>A reference to the name in an <a href="executor.html">Executor</a> element.
         If this attribute is enabled, and the named executor exists, the connector will
         use the executor, and all the other thread attributes will be ignored.</p>
    </attribute>
  </attributes>

  </subsection>

  <subsection name="Standard Implementation">

  <p>
  HTTP doesn't support more attributes that the ones listed above.</p>

  </subsection>
  
</section>


<section name="Nested Components">

  <p>None at this time.</p>

</section>


<section name="Special Features">


  <subsection name="HTTP/1.1 and HTTP/1.0 Support">

  <p>This <strong>Connector</strong> supports all of the required features
  of the HTTP/1.1 protocol, as described in RFC 2616, including persistent
  connections, pipelining, expectations and chunked encoding.  If the client
  (typically a browser) supports only HTTP/1.0, the
  <strong>Connector</strong> will gracefully fall back to supporting this
  protocol as well.  No special configuration is required to enable this
  support. The <strong>Connector</strong> also supports HTTP/1.0
  keep-alive.</p>

  <p>RFC 2616 requires that HTTP servers always begin their responses with
  the highest HTTP version that they claim to support.  Therefore, this
  <strong>Connector</strong> will always return <code>HTTP/1.1</code> at
  the beginning of its responses.</p>

  </subsection>


  <subsection name="Proxy Support">

  <p>The <code>proxy-name</code> and <code>proxy-port</code> attributes can
  be used when JBoss Web is run behind a proxy server.  These attributes
  modify the values returned to web applications that call the
  <code>request.getServerName()</code> and <code>request.getServerPort()</code>
  methods, which are often used to construct absolute URLs for redirects.
  Without configuring these attributes, the values returned would reflect
  the server name and port on which the connection from the proxy server
  was received, rather than the server name and port to whom the client
  directed the original request.</p>

  <p>For more information, see the
  <a href="../proxy-howto.html">Proxy Support HOW-TO</a>.</p>

  </subsection>



  <subsection name="SSL Support">

  <p>You can enable SSL support for a particular instance of this
  <strong>Connector</strong> by setting the <code>secure</code> attribute to
  <code>true</code>.  In addition, you may need to configure the following
  attributes:</p>

  <attributes>

    <attribute name="algorithm" required="false">
      <p>The certificate encoding algorithm to be used. This defaults to the Sun
      implementation (<code>SunX509</code>). For IBM JVMs you should use the
      value <code>IbmX509</code>. For other vendors, consult the JVM
      documentation for the correct value.</p>
    </attribute>

    <attribute name="clientAuth" required="false">
      <p>Set to <code>true</code> if you want the SSL stack to require a
      valid certificate chain from the client before accepting a connection.
      Set to <code>want</code> if you want the SSL stack to request a client
      Certificate, but not fail if one isn't presented. A <code>false</code>
      value (which is the default) will not require a certificate chain
      unless the client requests a resource protected by a security
      constraint that uses <code>CLIENT-CERT</code> authentication. See the
      <a href="../ssl-howto.html">SSL HowTo</a> for an example.</p>
    </attribute>

    <attribute name="keystoreFile" required="false">
      <p>The pathname of the keystore file where you have stored the
      server certificate to be loaded.  By default, the pathname is
      the file "<code>.keystore</code>" in the operating system home
      directory of the user that is running JBoss Web. If your
      <code>keystoreType</code> doesn't need a file use <code>""</code>
      (empty string) for this parameter.</p>
    </attribute>

    <attribute name="keystorePass" required="false">
      <p>The password used to access the server certificate from the
      specified keystore file.  The default value is "<code>changeit</code>".
      </p>
    </attribute>

    <attribute name="keystoreProvider" required="false">
      <p>The name of the keystore provider to be used for the server
      certificate. If not specified, the list of registered providers is
      traversed in preference order and the first provider that supports the
      <code>keystoreType</code> is used.
      </p>
    </attribute>

    <attribute name="keystoreType" required="false">
      <p>The type of keystore file to be used for the server certificate.
      If not specified, the default value is "<code>JKS</code>".</p>
    </attribute>

    <attribute name="sslProtocol" required="false">
      <p>The version of the SSL protocol to use.  If not specified,
      the default is "<code>TLS</code>".</p>
    </attribute>

    <attribute name="ciphers" required="false">
      <p>A comma seperated list of the encryption ciphers that may be used.
      If not specified, then any available cipher may be used.</p>
    </attribute>

    <attribute name="keyAlias" required="false">
      <p>The alias used to for the server certificate in the keystore. If not
      specified the first key read in the keystore will be used.</p>
    </attribute>

    <attribute name="truststoreFile" required="false">
      <p>The TrustStore file to use to validate client certificates.</p>
    </attribute>

    <attribute name="truststorePass" required="false">
      <p>The password to access the TrustStore. This defaults to the value
      of <code>keystorePass</code>.</p>
    </attribute>

    <attribute name="truststoreProvider" required="false">
      <p>The name of the truststore provider to be used for the server
      certificate. If not specified, the list of registered providers is
      traversed in preference order and the first provider that supports the
      <code>truststoreType</code> is used.
      </p>
    </attribute>

    <attribute name="truststoreType" required="false">
      <p>Add this element if your are using a different format for the
      TrustStore then you are using for the KeyStore.</p>
     </attribute>

     <attribute name="allowUnsafeLegacyRenegotiation" required="false">
       <p>Is unsafe legacy TLS renegotiation allowed which is likely to expose
       users to CVE-2009-3555, a man-in-the-middle vulnerability in the TLS
       protocol that allows an attacker to inject arbitrary data into the user's
       request. If not specified, a default of <code>false</code> is used.</p>
     </attribute>

  </attributes>

  <p>For more information, see the
  <a href="../ssl-howto.html">SSL Configuration HOW-TO</a>.</p>

  </subsection>

</section>


</body>

</document>
